All right we'll let them do that I'll do it I'm going to do so what type...may be used in
...we've actually done anything...that...for real like...the national
...rx you guys get about twenty minutes in, come on,
up and...you everybody's like...doing so,
one of the really cool things about types group is that you can take what to
know today and apply it to once you want to
do to move to the future but moved the...today and, what's before
jumping what's your favorite feature...the feature probably the is...the typing side of america strong type
a strong typing to be able to get intelligence on all the different variables working with
...responses come back from like a hp requests to get the strong
typing comes back and I think it's also that...writing javascript
...javascript magma...six today and not worry about which browsers
...of a single answer another no I don't know I'm long-winded what's your favorite one which are...my
...just killed...so, for those of use...you'll know that you can actually basically right
yes six modern code today so that you kind of future
prove your apps for tomorrow and that's actually one of my favorite features there's a particular company
...filming I'm not allowed to say the name I heard about
two years ago they decided to move to types group and as a result,
you know, now two years ago there now basically do any a six code and have been
...last two years which is really awesome from meanness...let's jump in
and talk about some of the highlights here so one of my favorite features in
addition to what we just said is I mentioned earlier you can take your existing code
and by existing...meaner existing javascript...andrew has you know,
many thousand lines...you literally can
renamed the file to dot ts and it could just work now that doesn't buy
you much but it basically is something
...sits on top of the javascript so it's not this own language
a lot of people kind of think that type scripts like its own often lala land, you know,
and, language somewhere and, you know, it's not?
It's also very modular so one of the cool things a lot of you probably do dot
net I suspect and it's module in the sense that you can do classes if you want which
we'll talk about that coming up you can actually do something called modules you can do internal and external
modules and this is a way to basically divided...code in the buckets just I
could do almost like namespaces kind of in dot net and there's even some
more how about large apps andrew that's a big thing that's a big
...hard to maintain large applications with lots of javascript
or that are based on just javascript keeping track of the different files that are
...memory but
and your memory but with types...was going to give you the ability to do is that with the different
editors they're aware of all of the files that are in your project makes a lot easier to figure out
...intel's sense type completion...makes things a lot easier so that's helping
on the modularity of keeping things much more organized like
we're used to using namespaces inside like a us csharp or bb
dot net and also helps in the scaleable side of your application structure making it easier to
do to keep things much better organized state guides a even smaller
...benefit but really for those building some larger-scale...meeting, you know,
more than five lines of code so the ones I mean the...if it rarer because
benefit from that so we're going to look at strong typing coming up so it is called type script for
...you do have the ability to have strings and
numbers and arrays and the boolean and things like that in your code if you want
optional middle kind of talk about as we move forward tooling support so
me download visual studio...
Anybody amir goal it's actually pretty freaking cool I'm loving it,
...I had up to the last moth actually to be play with it and
it's awesome so whether it's visual studio code or visual studio
or sublime text for web storm web storm has awesome support
...a text notepad...I'm sure...or something but maybe they'll have plus is the
another announcement notepad has extensibility that's the big enough
for this talk is moi.
Anyway,
and, then the file thing is...will look at some of...coming up here is epics crypt six
...actually doing native via six like rot your six code right now not a whole lot okay well,
a lot of you raise your hand for...script those so you are doing...six you just may not know you're
doing...yes, six if you haven't heard about all the cool new things are going to have support
for classes and modularity...structuring and
angle on there's literally this huge list of features and types script one-dot five
is currently kind of in a early-stage but, you can get to...get helping things
and supports a broad-range of the six features and that's why I say if you move the
type script you can actually start leveraging...today so that in, you know,
two years you're not going man I wish I would've teletypes for,...
So, with this what why is...the significance here of type script and then
we're talking about today building single page apps angular so we got to
links up here that you go take a look at back last yeargoogle who
is behind angular they announce something called at script and their whole
thing was basically saying that...types script there's a couple things that we want to add to it fast-forward until
I guess this past march...just a few months ago it was announced that google's
...working with microsoft to extend type script a little bit farther than where was already
and google's
drop their idea of at...now what's the significance of this it means that now
anglers being built with type script one-dot five for the entire source code
...this link right here is from keynote...was given...engine com which is
a angular conference salt lake city the person on that screen there that's jonathon
turner from the microsoft type script team explaining how everything kinda went through
...the next slide also has another...a showing bread
green and igor from the angular team that shows how they're building
...using alta they're using typed script to build all of angular and then from there is being compiled
to different languages javascript and darden all that but this shows that
what they're doing is they're putting we have first-class support for all this stuff right...the
...using with...we're...for angular and that's what's cool about subscript,
you know,...do a lerner so you get a...quite a bit I hope you raise your hand you raise your
Heard about yesterday.
But, anyway, the...
But, you know, whether you doing that or knockout orgy where your amber or
...a really cool new...I'd been looking at...right js which I'm gone now that's a good they're
...you know, you can do with anything so I...of the features that I'm going to
show you just a real quick introduction for those that have done types group in kind of what looks like and
...will jump into this actual app that use all the school stuff so all right strongly types.
Variable strongly
typed parameters that's all very cool class supports very cool now
...want to emphasize on this so I had the opportunity the sit down and do an interview with
a anders...and was a little actually nervous for the what
...that nervous nowadays but I was for that one because, you know,...the...wrote this and csharp and
...everything...and pascal everything I've ever
use pretty much but anyway we I have slide up and said
type script classes and...nor are we going to change that and I was like okay what do you are doing as
...you gotta make sure people know that you don't have to use classes you can still
do functional programming if you want so, you know, by functional programming
...stuff we write today in javascript and I'm as I mentioned earlier
it still works here so just kind of want to
emphasize that yes there is class support but in certain circles
javascript some people like that and you don't have to
...should down that road interface is one of the nice things I like about the fact that we
have both classes and interfaces inside of type script is that when somebody like me when I came
from csharp I came from a sp net necessary doing a lot more client-side
development with javascript it's different...mean I've asked everybody in the room how many of you
...really good javascript developers I love doing this how menu considers of really good javascript
developers be osh pleasure n couple people now how many view phone the category that I
fall into which is an hackett my way through this javascript thing for the last decade?
For those of you on that are watching this on the video basically everybody else raise their hand of course...
initially like right you went to the site you saw the drop down the menus you...source...that library plug-in
yours got a bunch...through a bunch of...and their left and right we've done that before but I like about is
that classes and interfaces and generics these things make it easy to go from
a strongly type language with a...net or anything else
...working on traditionally server-side stuff to move into javascript write
the same style of stuff that I'm used to writing inside of javascript I'm doing it
...type scripts compiling down to javascript making life a lot easier for
me so whether it's give you a real-life example real quick...I think everybody relate to that
...talked about so, how many of use ij query plug-in where your pass
and settings and how many of used...plug-in that maybe the documentation was a little we
that doesn't happen doesn't happen and you may be had...look at the source code I know
it's it was probably my...your stuff but anyway you don't know what
...with interfaces you can actually make
an interface that in essence maps hey here's...
this particular function call needs as the parameters so just I can csharp?
Or java or whatever you use and you could actually go in and make,
you know,...interface to clarify the...and very cool
feature the generics will go too deep into that but it's the same thing you do now you have
...t you can do list a ti engineer types for modularity of
already touched on we'll talk about that...we jump in the type definite, yeah,
type definition of my talk more about this we get into...the...experience what
that looks like but essentially what this does is that when you're when you're building your own application
and, you're running your own types profiles everything you're...intelligence for all the classes the
methods the properties and stuff that you're writing but then that you run into you'll find really quickly that
it's not always writing your own stuff you're always using another library,
for example, angular j query and you want that kind of visibility into those things like
...was just talking about a second goes how do you get that stuff
war-type definitions when someone has done is they've essentially
...signature for this external javascript library so that when you go
...dot of something to go-go do a selector inside of
j query or angular dot module how you get intelligence for that type script is
going to be using a type definition...project that has a ton of these things and
...called definitely typed will show you how we said this project up to take advantage of that and
make our lives easier doing development absolutely very cool in
fact visual studio code is based on this very concept this type definitions using
types group behind-the-scenes to get the...that we get very...
Iso rep this part up and...at some stuff here so,
it all compiles to javascript you now have three options you compiled years three years five
years six...six still kind of looks like...five but I think eventually once all the browser support
your six will be compiling down to just regular
your six code that's something you can change either in your build settings if
...like...or...these tools we're going to talk about ...visual studio you just write click on your project
and you can say hey this is my output...I want...three because I can't
support for instance javascript properties or something like that so, very cool and
...features as well so let's jump in to a quick little just run through here.
And, we're going-to do is kind of walk you through the real basics of types group for those that
maybe...
All right so first let me do...some normal stuff here.
Let's just do...
And,...y equals five like a number
and let's make a function called ad that takes let's call it num one and to just
a kind of...up hear what you're seeing on the left-hand...reading types...left-hand side this site types
...laying dough types...dot org has a playground site words compiling the
type script on the left-hand side to javascript live on the right-hand side using the types
...compiler so you have a someone have experience in visual studio and much the other
editors what you're seeing...what you're seeing is a self compiling down javascript while these
...in the types group and, yeah,
and, I should...you go to...scribbling dot org to get to this you just click on that...play
icon up there and you'll notice that as...kind of summed it up real nice look,
what I type on the left which is types group right now but you're going no it's not
as javascript but, look,
what it output on the right okay just pretty normal stuff and that's why I said
is superset you can take your existing code just plug it on
...and you're good to go now what's going
to happen here those javascript gurus the one that raise your hand...probably this?
What's going to happen if we run with an alert on this result we're going
to get anyone any ideas within the numbers throw it out I didn't add, yeah,
we're going to get enough...
...detail you might want to fill in your function yes let me go ahead and return types...we...do that
for you...yeah, it's so cool that I was expecting...for automate that for.
All right let's run...you'll notice we get...see that but a you do your
...thing...different setup than I do on my computer but anyway we got
fifty five which is obviously not right now hopefully of unit...and things like that everybody likes to
say they do testing but not everybody does how many actually do unit testing for real?
Pretty good overall...we need
to protectorate thing but I like the idea of doing it...
...of...a good for you so what we can do a types
...is this it's called types group because we can come in and say hey this
is a number and this guy right here notice
it automatically went read on me says type string is not assign will to type number of
the now if you have an editor that recognise some of these type script these are kind of compilers if you
will such as visual studio visual studio code and even sublime have some
plug-in for and some others then you instantly know...you know,
I screw this up now in this case we typed is I don't know that's
the big deal but we'll keep will keep going here.
Come on, down to why will also say that's
...number okay so did catch this it still has the output there
but we're really gets cool is we can come into here.
And, type these guys and you'll notice you put a
colon so it's a little backwards from maybe...csharp code...you put the
...in to type it and now let me just to make
a little more obvious let's pass in like,
you know, fred right here and see that read squiggly we instantly get
pretty awesome so I'm able to know right away that hey this isn't, you
know, valid saying even better than that watch when I let me just pull this out.
you'll notice that...get full...sense there in this case, you know, depends on your editor...to work.
...there but you'll notice that right away we're able to say hey it's a number and
...number so we can pass in and now I can come up and obviously,
you know, fix this guy.
Figured out.
And, we could do x and y something like that are very basically
you get the idea now you have numbers you have strains...look at that here
and just...you have arrays any...those your base once and then you can also deal with
moles and some others types there's even an any if I were to do this andrew.
What ends up happening because I know we?
Do this as far as types what is the type of this any guesses?
They will actually infer okay we'll infer
...that's a runtime thing ...defaults to any it's called so,
yeah, it does have type inference so it's smart enough to try to
figured out but it's really kind of like...and that.
Now because I assigned it your rights it'll figured out in ultimately will be
that but, you notice that if I take that out and run it it's still going to do fifty-five.
All right that's kinda like that's a nice little trick when you're actually trying to build-out
your like the types for your building like interfaces and such and you don't know what's a certain kind of an
object going to be the comes back like if you're making requesting hp service we'll show you
...and one-hour interfaces how we have set up to the response comes back
...like a generic ones as a coming back in any it's a collection of
...so...way to cheat a little bit.
We do one of the thing here so
that is an eds six class.
...types...classes well types group is based upon ias six concepts now
...that maybe have seen this or probably...very
nice like that looks like the code I write you on the server maybe.
So, we now have a constructor here and what I can do is even put in
...do a little variable field...want to call and now we could say
this dot name equals name so for those csharp gurus in the
crowd looks a lot like csharp except for you actually use the
keyword constructor there to do your work notice on the right
...is now output?
Now if you've ever done patterns at all revealing module pattern for
instance we're starting to get close to that here.
Very cool now another cool thing is.
You know-how many want to use prototype you have any actually truly understand
prototype this because the.
By in javascript the one person or two that raise your hand...get...prototypes kind of
tricky and javascript another cool thing we can do is let's say we have a manager.
And, I could say manager extends.
Person if I...red-eye can.
now I just picked up the name and we could even come down here now and save
rm gr equals new.
Manager.
All right and then on my manager we say manager dots and we can
start the dive into that
...now right now manager extends person doesn't have a constructor because what you have to do.
Is I'm a hard coded you can actually call-in to the
base class amr do andrew here because he so cool?
And, now notice the read
...goes away so it's basically telling me if I...guys the air that hey yet, you know,
you extended it but you didn't call the base...which is a requirement
was super and now I can say manager dots and
there's name and we could say change it to, you know, for whatever.
All right so that's kind of some of the basics of types group and some...things we're going to start
seen is that you can do classes you can do types.
You can do generics you can do interfaces all those fun stuff.
All rights are jump over let's talk a little bit about...
Back to this we're back let's talk a little about the how part of this use all kind
...what the why...saw a little bit of developing it but it can jump...say well how do I get this
in my project...how it take advantage of this the cool thing is the majority there's a lot
...out there's dan said that already have types...support builds right in the one that's missing from this
list here is visual studio code I'd recommend that you actually go take a look at the video from
a session from yesterday that john...and air
...encrusted yesterday I talked about visual studio code...really cool because it shows
you the visual studio code when you're writing javascript even takes advantage of
...script features to give you some...even if you're not using
...just running javascript uses the type script engine and the definitely
typed definitions to take advantage that gives more intelligence there's other ones that we
have like sublime brackets is a javascript editor is an editor that's actually written
javascript those guys have type script support they do...extension model but,
the thing I really want you take away from this is that you can use anything because we can have
a build process using some sort of build engine to automate the process
of taking advantage of types script we taken advantage this inside of our project so let
me show you a little bit of what we've done here with our project now...
Going to give you a list of all of the or a link to this
works we can grab this but essentially what are project does is already...type scripts and we
run everything through an engine called goal so gulp of those your familiar
if you're traditional asp dot net stuff you're familiar with the tool called microsoft build that's
microsoft's build engine...more of a configuration setup where use xml to define
...in those task go do stuff with gulp you instead are using the javascript to
write those tasks so you get kind of a full stack experience here so here you see I've got a task
here called compiled ts that's going to go compile all of our
type script in the project and the way we've defined it is the very top of
this file we have a configuration reference that were making that we've configuration file that
were referencing by open that file of guide couple different things saying like where would you find the source
of the application where you...the source of everything within this project
...the actual angular application where should all the stuff get compiled
two-zero more compiling all the time script using gulp we're creating new folder called
slashed js and putting it all there we don't check that file
...source control or that folder insource control...just like a dls far
as work concern is a generated output that we don't need to keep insource control
the compilers going to do that for us as a couple other settings here as well but what this does
with a couple things we I showed you the compile ts you can even do
...lending of your type script so lending is basically going
to look at my code styles so now I can type in gulp
dash tr ts lent so if I come over here?
Is a little dangers here but...let's go to our project?
See the note there where moammar
...so let's go gulp.
Ts was lent was much has name again thinkers tuzla ts
one yet ts what actually called lent.
What does can do is look at all of my type script and see if thirty issues with...I went back to one of my types
...files and I remove something so like if I come over here let's do one that's not
going to make that much of an impact legal at a space to this over here I've got some definition
...inside of this ts
...file down here that says hey trailing spaces are no good so in this
space here and found that one error and reported to me incitement
...decode style thing we've got other task that are in
...well that I would recommend you take a look at some...you just copy them...put
...in your project one of the challenges that you run into with type...at least I keep running
into that if I come over here like this routes file
I'm referencing things we'll dive into the code
...project a minute but you see I'm actually annotating this parameters coming in
...as an angular type that's one example...come over here to module
...annotating all of these guys different settings there's interface that
we define the trick is that...like I put these
...references in there but the type the compiler doesn't know what those things are unless I
reference them from within the same file so what you see if...the very top the file...to
the slash references and what these guys are doing appear the very top is the referencing a
...ts file which is a definitely type file or type
definition but in this case these are just collections of existing
...type definitions that we've acquired so what you see...on the deduct
ts here's a list of all the ones that we've required from the definitely type
project that were referencing our project using throughout our project that's great we've gone doing
grab those guys using the definitely type tools but we want to be able to have all of our types
group files referenced as well so I have another one called expense at deduct
ts so this one is a list of all of our types group files we have the entire project
I want a reference to that and every single one of my files right here
...I don't have to remember okay which files may using this and this file...which references
...to add here and you...messy at the top very messy so what we did using goal
is that if you if we take a look at the expense one again you'll notice that I
have my own style of like commenting so I've got like a slash and open curly bracket of
...down to the bottom I have a closing one what I did is I created a
task over here called...ts rafts and what this one does it says go
...all the types group files in the current project be
it then pipes them through this engine and it says
...a plug-in called inject and it's going to look for these two
tag so start tagging
...tag...take all those files that you find in write them out this is
words doing online twenty-four white them right...to that file this strings
on building up is expense...deduct ts file all the time with
the files that I'm adding you're wondering well it's kinda interesting it's
...I see how that would help you tell me every time at a file and...go riyadh this not really because
one of the other cool things about type script is we
have these watchers now what this guy is going to do is that I just go and type in
gulp and what we'll do isnow look at all of my types group files throughout the entire
projects that's being define their online seventy-three look all my type script files
every single time you see one of those files change I want you to
rerun ts lent then run compile ts then run
gen ts rafts so what I'm doing my developments pretty cool that's pretty cool
...I can just say...over here on the side is going to go run those things you see
I've got that one little error if I come back and fix that problem
...was that problem again...the fear that was on...
line five so we go to add browse line five ago the top let's remove that space
...save I can't get back there fast enough but what you see is it ran
again right here and it said was go rerun ts lent compile and all that so I usually
have that up on one window while I'm doing my development...read stuff pops up
...you want to pay attention to it sprays like you have...your testing and there's well and it's just a really
is constant continuous development experience...real quick for those that are just do and
pure visual studio it actually will build in the ability to reference the files so if you're
gone advice...that measles too you don't have to now I like having a separate process because of
...lengthy and all that but if you just want to use...visual studio not the code
but visual still even visual...code will do...but a lot of you might use,
you know, different addresses are different operates...different editor's so we're kind of shoney's something
worse on everything, yeah, and, that's the we're doing at
...for that reason for the reason of showing where works everywhere this project you open it up...any
...you want it will work visual studio I guess we have...a real name for visual studio
...just...seo koess code...one but the big visual studio not the
new visual studio they announced this week the big I even has plug-in surprise
...that you can add and the current production version visual studio to get support
for gulp visual studio twenty fifteen is going to have that big write-in so microsoft
as even adopting this tools well spree slick there's a bunch of different
plug-ins ridiculous number plug-in so yeah, so, you just take a look at that's how we build the project
up it's got some good samples in their for-you to take a look at so let me talk a little bit
here about office three sixty...why do you want to consider this for using it for your development
experience I've got a couple points up here on the slide but there's something...point that I want to make here
...of my opinion on this we work in the cloud we understand there's things like
...so infrastructures a services...hardware we
have paths platform as a service platforms a services going to give us, you know,
the ability to use different services...building are different applications what I like...we also have
sas solvers a service that's like office three sixty five you pay subscription to get some different
capabilities what I like to think of with office three sixty five and sharepoint is
e paths as a developer I like to go build my own applications I don't need...want to
...something else but what's cool about this there's a lot of things that office three
sixty five can provide and all those things can be taken advantage of inside of my
app you need workflow sharepoint provides that do need user profile information
and augmented from different sources sharepoint has that what
about manage metadata for to for tagging a hierarchy and stuff these things
...a lot of different services that we can take advantage of the app that we've done uses sharepoint
list store...the data for like employees and stuff like that and, expenses
and then we use one drawing for business or the files api from office three sixty five to
show a reference to those different files...the lights working thank goodness because
...readily...looking right at...so,
some of the challenges though when you're building applications
associated with office three sixty five you have to choose like if it's going to traditional office
three sixty-five app is going to be a cloud app...going to be a sharepoint hosted at meaning
does the app reside inside of sharepoint all the files and get surface to the client
or does it lives somewhere else that's the cloud...and live-in as...eight of us are
...or wherever there's a server-side component to it you
gotta decide another thing too is that when you're doing this you need to always protect these o
off access tokens that you're going to use to authenticate with a services protected with o off
...or uses ought to for
is authentication model you need to protect these access tokens this stuff is like cache once?
You get an access token anybody can use it if I draw between...on the ground and you come up and
grabbing head down the street go get a coffee the person on the...not going to say that's
...twenty you can't buy a coffee with that is going to get coffee let-me know I'll drop the twenty just bring you
So, you need to make sure that you protect that so that stuff is going to stay on the server you need to usually
create some sort of an intermediary...and that's actually what we had to do with this project
initiallymany months ago and before some microsoft announce something that will show
in just a minute and,...client-side ads are going to need to have if you build
app is a hundred-percent client-side html
css and javascript like the one that we have if you want to talk to a office three
sixty five service initially when they were released we had to have
an intermediary service that would go talk to that service on
our behalf because those services didn't support
...domain calls so we could make those...in the browser...of the server-side so we
...to have an intermediary that was protecting the tokens and making those calls on our behalf me tell
you that was a lot of fun I waswell,...tongue-in-cheek...there so,
what microsoft did here is they created this thing ...news support for a new kind ofoff
flow or sorry there's no offload called the implicit flow and that allows us to have
an authentication model to get the access token without him to protected on those
on the server-side that support was also when they
...that support they also create a library or I guess it's a pair of libraries called eighty al
So, eighty al js is a client-side solution for creating this authentication model
it was designed initially to work with angular us before they went vone with this
they actually split out...there's an eighty...js and eighty al angular js
and what they'll tell you is that is really designed not to be used as just the core
eighty al js is designed to be used inside of angular you'll see
why will show you some of the code on what it does for you if you want to
...support for some of the other frameworks that are out there like amber like ...like I
think a really earlier if you want and support for those you can do that I know that one of the developers in the team
...been working on a support for amber but it's really cool because allows do all
the authentication really easy and actually you did a lot of work with them on that and there's
actually a really funny quote when they went ga and vone if you switch over real quick I show this
quote here so...the analysis that...everything's done it's all working and stuff there's a
...reaches ga and then here's a quote that dan had as I had
exact same experience dan says it was so easy I'm still in stock...trying to figure out of it really
worked literally was in the chrome tools goal and I think that work
...the network traffic...no way just is works so actually you have a
tori who's a friend from the as your team he's like can I use that...
...pretty close like what...of...blue's the same experience I got it by put
...very little code to get working will show you that what...we show because you...once you
...runactually...static...that first...you have this kind implicit
flow works here and the app and all this fun stuff and that
...the end you'll be able to get the ...code if you want and kinda go from there so,
you want I'll just...don't you explain the server back-up you...now he's been always going...get
...yeah, go ahead go ahead you I don't...password because now, you know, two hundred michael's
There's no we were on a logging actually like...goes too fast...
We are screens to get reminds it was also be...use
...moving on moi.
Sketch language knows...extra and ok so we have a rather obvious
log in this is on purpose so that anyone that tries it can see it and,
there's even text...click
login but go ahead and do it and you're going to see that we instantly go off
overhear to our leisure eighty login go ahead andloggers in andrew?
And, was so-call about this is we literally
...any of that code to do the
...we didn't have to worry about the id tokens and this is now
haitian sharepoint list data here this
...can...for a prototype of...we have you know,
company data is already and sharepoint we're not moving it, you know, too many people are using these lists
so let's build an applicant is leverage that data that's kind of what's going on here so
the data itself is just customers and expenses and then this is thailand
tiny into the files api was coming from my one drive for business
folder or account and then ...out real quick you guys
...it'll say like redirect the right there sign sign-out in progress
and then you'll go kind of back to the app now the way this works is you actually have
to in as your we're not going to have a whole lot of time to show this...you...the as
...quickly shown the app I've now voted andrew to be a code monkey for me because
his laptop so he'll better...typing physio so he's got
a log into as your ...in as you'll have down to bottom left you'll have as
your actor...and they were using after directory and here as director
directorate okay we have a few it's actually very cool what they've done.
he now can drill into is after directory and...applications
...and expense app or expense manager their application and yet actually shown the
...real fast so what you normally do you can walk through and
you to pick from gallery or do your own app so if
anyone's ever registered one of your apps with facebook or twitter or some
other service you have to go register the app give the url and things and they're going to get back
...client secrets and all that and...let them kind of...the basic screens here?
Right so this go off and create a nap and they were going to get basically a little, you know,
client id that we need and then there's a ten jump over the one that we
...have use the one so we'll jump in here.
And, once...several down for me right there bc that
...id so eight-hour js which we're going to show
you needs this okay and then also show real quick...endpoints...the...there we go
viewing points all right now notice that really lovely guid whatever you like to call
...that's something we need as well so this kind of two things we need for...that we can work with
that little guy right there again all right so now you can see that what you do you go registry
rap and go to the very bottom there and see the url reply url
...sorry that normally obviously would be a real, you know,
...were he local host but it does work local...which is very cool and,
any other quick talk about security so that's important when one of things you can do what...is...create the app you're actually going
to give the app permissions do stuff now that the app is actually doing these things
...called delegated permissions so what you're saying is
that if someone goes to use the app I'm going to allow the user to grant
the app permissions to do these kinds of things so in this case here I've said I...to an
...an application with a few options down here there's our...there's the unify
api that was that you...talked about this week sharepoint online exchange online we've
...to an added sharepoint...on the delegated permissions we've chosen things like you can read
and write user files we didn't really need that we just need the read user files that's the one drive for business
or the files api we can read and write items to site collections
...the site a sites api...office three sixty five which you may
...just the rest api but you can see other things here like management of data that one's new
we got the ability to go through work with user profiles and such but these permissions here your
...will need this and the first-time you're user goes to use this app they'll
be prompted to say hey this at needs these permissions will you grant this
app permissions to for your account and you have to say yes or no for to go through
...grant those one do you should definitely keep in mind here is this
...enable sign...profiles for the as you're active directory you're always going to have that one
check I don't recommend you turn off if you do...you'll see why need to turn on because you won't be able to
...I'll tell you what happens you waste four hours of your life trying to figure out why you
can't login that hasn't happened hasn't happened right not that happened to me
butthat's I've heard that's what I have a friend that's done that before and is not a good thing right
...budget it's one of those things that when you're building the in visual studio the tools we have
for office three sixty five when you go through the
ad connected service when you creating an office three sixty-five app or website that uses the
...sixty-five api is it creates this application for you and...those different
permissions for you so you can add different permissions and there...constantly working adding more stuff
that's pretty slick so that's how we create the application here you want...value
a run in sorry what...the rest of time we got about fifteen minutes I think so the rest
...time now you've seen a little bit...type script you've seen a little bit how to set up with gulp or you could
just use the big-boy visual studio we'll call it gives you a little boy and big-boy?
...that term we're going to do now is walk through some of the key features the app I mean the
...you'll build download you want to get too we
fall lot-of patterns and things like that were negative time to go into all that but so, we start off here in this
...module that ts and you'll notice online ate there are actually defining
...module so if you done angular before this is basically creating
the bucket for app we're going to put stuff in and notice we intel sense
well that ts ddot-cdot ts...the very top that's actually pulling
in this type definition file that...already talked about and you
could by the way you gotta definitely...dot org if you're interested and,
there's ways you can even automate this but again in the interest of time will just mention it so definitely
types dot org we'll get to the access to all this so once we do the module
notice that we also then configure a few key...so,
actually jump down the highland seventeen eighteen...forming so first off we configure the routes
...standard angular routing there's nothing real fancy
there pretty normal stuff so we can load are different views for those that are maybe new to a
little bit the second-line this is the key one here that gives us the act as
you're active directory login and this is a...
So, that calls into this
eight-hour dot configure you'll notice so first off notice that we have a...top which is a
types group module we have a class were exporting out of the module
...new that that's kinda how it's...work...as well you basically
expose what you want and the other stuff is sort of implicitly private if you don't
exporter to build get too and,
then notice that were injecting in some things here like the http provider well what's going to
happen is every ajax requests that happens.
A...intercept that that's the eight-hour dotting euler whatever it...file
...andrew...there's the...we...we clicked on view
endpoints to get to the...there's the client id that's the one that was in the
app application page we just showed you so we're just grabbing those from a constance file yeah,
run-off...real quick and they're they are and
then the other thing we have to specify just real quick much talk about...yeah,
so, if you if you go back we look at this you'll see we're also
...a collection of endpoints into the initialization for eight-hour provider in every
...this whole object we're...and h http provider so
...the service that we have
an eighty al the creative for angular it's now attaching itself to the as dan said
hp interceptor but we have to tell it when you care about the authentication
...so if I come over and look at the constance again...is this the object we have
...ad in points and it's got a syntax of basic of
...of having object and then we'll have a property and a value for
the objects each one of those properties is going to be a different
endpoint now on the left-hand side the property name necks the first part of the
...explain why we need the second the right side that you see over
here the right side of this is the resource id that we need and some of the office three
sixty five services so what's happening here what I'm
telling eighty al js is the say whenever you see
in http request come out of angular that starts with that url with that
...and using that resource id that's...resource and you need to make
sure that you include theoff to access token in the header
and authorization header for every request it does that magically dan
...to do this authentication if I'm not already logged in
...will...js will hold that request it will send-me over
...as your ad make me login combat
...access token create that...recreate that rest request that or
the http request that I was making from angular put the authorization header
into it then make the requesting get the response it does all of that stuff automatically...
refresh tokens yet to get this eighty-eight algeria's stuff working all we had to do was
create this little settings object which I guess we just did it for...ability or make it easier follow
meters and you just we wrote this one's...that's all we did get the authentication
...working that's freaking cool that's why I was like is this really working because
it's like that in write that much snow...show the other part...the routes how we secured
the routes so the other part two of the rows that you see some of these routes like the login route one that's
...for...force authentication here because we're going to redirect you over...of the other things that the eighty-eight
...dashed ...angular dot js file does is the get it
look let's add another property routes called require eighty login if
it's not there but the default is false but what this does it says hey within the app if you go to
one of those urls I'm going to force you to go make sure your authenticated if you're not
...you over to
...go login so if I give a deep link into this you might be looking at this going wait a minute this is all
javascript I can see what security was not secures I can just type in your own get whatever I need I don't know about
you but I don't care if you can see the source code for my application what I really care about is
I don't want you to see the data that's the important part of the apps seeing what the views look
like that doesn't matter you show me once...me your outlook I don't I...don't there's no
email and that is useless to me I want to see your email I don't really want to your
arm channeling the nsa but I don't want to see your stuff okay but.
Okay, so, we are...configuration what you want to
...so, let's wrap up by looking at some of the...three sixty five let's look at the factories and
factoring source services...you...the data services file service to the data one
...will do file requests all type of and, then we'll jump gap up with that so,
the last piece is that home page to show loaded in a bunch of customer
data right and we mention we're kind of assuming that we have a company where, you know,
a lot of our data is maybe in a database but some of the...is...sharepoint as well we want
to get to both resources maybe one pulling from a local database and from sharepoint so yes,...down
for me and first off there's a bunch of functions in here and this is a pretty big
type script class this is an angular service and you'll notice that we have
some restful type of...done much sharepoint rest before you'll recognize this so
yep that code right there this is were actually calling now and the beauty of
...and what we just showed you is now we're out of the business of having to worry about if they should be
getting this or not based upon the http...resource management...the
tokens and all that fun stuff with all off which is really fun to write by hand?
It does all that so now all we're doing is basically saying hey angular...http
standard get angle grab the url and then when it comes back I'm just key
seen some properties and you'll notice there's a case props and stuff like that that's all that really matter but
that is just massage...the data we get back and then ultimately it's going to pass it to angular
controller which thing goes to the view that's the first factory you're really
...going to care about this...a style that we...the matter...the when sharepoint gives the data back
is a title cases it camel case and we're just making
we just changing the way the data comes back to the objects are similar to the other javascript object we have
the application this is a style thing...nothing...or anything else forget about them and on the
kurds there, yeah, so, are jump over the files one so the other one we...the files api
...files service to talk to the files and
point this one here I've got a little constructor...crane as you can see that we've actually set up
...injecting different things like the hp service location service this is pretty cool
...about this keyword right here, you know, when you create a class and you create different properties
online class and you want those you'll be able to pass them
...but you in your constructor but you want to make those properties private to be able to
use them throughout your app so when you are throughout your class so when you pass them in the
...constructor and then within the constructor it's like this dot whatever the name of that private property is
inset the value the...that's come in right now I'm talking about well one of the things that this does is that
this keyword private putting...before the
different primaries coming in what that's going to do is implicitly or behind-the-scenes is
creating an internal private member inside this class called in this
case here dollar http so that later I can do things like
this dot dollar http and use that service without having
to define some private properties up here and setting those values back so that's just a little
...him that often you can also do public you one-b public right...so,
in this case here we're doing I've got a method called get user files and...that's going to do is go create my
endpoint requests I'm just saying go to my one drive in point here you might have
...in the settings...referencing earlier going to the slash files get by
paths looking at my receipts folder and getting all the children all
the contents of that folder remember...that drop down the pop-up use all bunch of
pbs that's what this is getting and then here I'm executing the request and this is one of
the another one of the things I love about type script the response
...comes back from this service is not a
...response is just a bunch of json data comes back so you see there I've
got were on the side words says here's the day is coming back?
Right here's result now when I reference data like result
...data dot value what kind of data is that you any idea
...file with your awesome documentation know what does not
...use this is up here like I don't so, yeah,
we don't know what that is right we don't know...that is I mean it's the files api tells us what it is but
you've...go over and look at response that comes back and...properties like that
that's a pain the but so what I like to do is I come over here and I'll add-in I've
added an...said this is the
data comes back I want you to type it are once you treated as a type
called I data I http data response so if I come over here
in my shared folder I look at my interfaces what you'll see is I have one here called my
by data http my http data response and that's got
a data property on it and we cheated we just thrown any on their design ability to
...we were going to go all the way with that part of the demo but, you know,
what no problem because what I can do now
to type the data comes back instead of using any right here
it's going to be a collection of a bunch of different either you had about your factor real fast go akamai a
...your service the services in a?
Files the...files.
...share dot I...I tell you have one, yeah, so,
I typed in there once I got it in but would be nice if I didn't have to do that so what I
could have done is that within this interface here...not one was
made of interfaces instead of calling at any I could've
done I receipt and says and...the data comes back is a collection of
I receives those I receipts are where they down here they're going to
give me back id names web urls those are the different properties coming
...inside the json response so that now when I'm working with the data
...comes back I have strongly typed
information on that response not just some generic stuff that I have to remember what those different fields
work that's pretty cool it can...a little t is as...working...abuser
...different services whatever...the one right exactly, yeah, so,...to do this,
yeah, so, we can get that one done but, yeah, that was that's another one of the benefits there and
...all this question notation says that you may or may not get this object coming back
we may have done select statement...we didn't care about the aidid's and only gave me back the
...the web url.
Was doing show we hope was due mormon we're almost done here so let's wrap up with
just run-off to let's go to the customer control...whole...to show...the service those
...angular will know the you have views.
you have controllers and your controller typically calls off to a service to get the data that's what we're doing so
our to services that we just showed you the files and the data
service one they're reusable we can reuse those across any number of controllers in our
app to get our customers are expenses are files are all that fun so there's just a
quick example of data service online one of seven there is
being injected in typical angular type code in this case and we're then
...into this employees
service here to go get the data and we must have a reference on that one
...the right and then we get back to data you might notice ...wait they're real fast and
we'll wrap up here right that is another types group feature there's also...six feature now
those...before will probably recognize that in...six we
...a fat error typically because it does look like a bigger error
but it's replacement basically for anonymous functions and there's even some
other benefits will have time to get into on it but anyway, that's another type
script feature that really minimize the amount of code and I'll tell you to wrap up here I had to
...android that part because I don't have the key that low equals greater...my...especially keyboard.
When we had done with this app the first version of this was actually
...five normal javascript...and I spent I don't
know ten days so that...click sixty as?
I'm trying to send good enough we spent whatever it was it wasn't too long and by the time we
get done both of our responses were that was freaking awesome
because the I love javascript actually for a while as one or two people on the planet
this but I've always liked it actually and when we did this
littlewe were on skate like constantly and, you know,
we're like man I was really cool because the interfaces just made all the
difference it what I would recommend you do type script is one of those things to me when I first
jumped into this it was a little I say it was a little hard to kind of
wrapping my brain around you start...you kind of stub your toe a few times here and there but,
once I started using it for like two or three days I was absolutely in love with
the and same thing with this happen as I had...we build this one either turn around and
...another app but I had to do in javascript couldn't do...type...doing it as
a hands-on lab for someone so I couldn't like write the type script and compiled...javascript
...show the javascript I knew the users to write the javascript it was so painful going back to
...standard...your...now so like why, yeah, so,
I don't I...like...decision I did yesterday all the stuff that I'm doing now...javascript I use
type script even when doing no js server-side javascript is all using types...we
had a battle about we're going to make the gold file a...script as well but that's kind of like a
start making the go file type program...and that's going to what we need to have
...the goal file we needed to be javascript so...can compile the type script...we want...
shows like we can...is types group...just don't believe the js while?
But, yeah, it's pretty cool these two...that we have up here the second link is...take
you deeper inside the first link okay so what the first link is microsoft
...the office team ...site deb that office dot com has got tons of great resources and
documentation labs and samples and videos and training...a ridiculous amount
...resources that will help you get started we're doing office three
sixty five development there are different courses within
that role within the that are provided in there there's one repository and get
...that you see there called training content and office dev organization
that repository ismassive amount of useful information
...different courses there's a specific course that talks about building applications
that don't have ...application without microsoft technologies and that course that
were referencing seven dash to is you is building this applications
we give you this application to as a static kind of thing and you go through
a hands-on lab to start adding in a bunch of the eighty-eight algeria's to
add the dynamic pieces for calling the different rest api for the
sites api for the files api so good hands-on lab there and then the
solution or the final output of that lab I give you a link to a diving into the link
...really long but that's the sample...we're showing you here from the lab that you actually
end up building their so-if you want-to go check it out to great links for you'll get this all right
so wrap-up then I hope you get a pretty good idea about how with I
...is a learning curve...lady-like andrew said but once you get the hang
...script whether or not you need goal maybe you don't maybe you do or...one of those others if you're just
using pure visual studio you might choose not to use...we went through that we talked about eight
I'll and then obviously we talked about calling...the restful services with what files api...point
there's even others you could as well there so to wrap-up then I hope everybody gets a good
...for ...group angular and all that and definitely check out the sample if you're interested
in more detail thanks-a-lot everybody moi.